Darren Alexander Muliawan

608 E University Ave #613, Champaign, IL 61820 • (424) 386-8322 • darrenm2@illinois.edu

Education

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign

August 2017 – May 2019

Major: Statistics & Computer Science

- Relevant Coursework: Software Design Studio, System Programming, Algorithms & Models of Computation, Database Systems, Data Mining, Art and Science of Web Programming, Statistics Programming Methods, Methods of Applied Statistics, Statistical Computing
- Academic Standing: GPA 3.72

Diablo Valley College

August 2015 – May 2017

Pleasant Hill, California

• Academic Standing: GPA 3.84

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient in C++, Java, Python, SQL and R programming language.

Experienced with Git, REST Protocols, NoSQL, JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Django, and Firebase. Easy going and talkative person, but also a serious, hard worker, and a quick learner.

Work Experience

University of Illinois, Urbana – Champaign

June 2018 – August 2018

Data Analyst & Content Writer Intern, Student Money Management Center

- Collect needed information from newsletters that were sent on previous months
 - Present the data in graphs
 - Suggest and discuss with other team members about what contents should be included for the next newsletters

Axioo, Surabaya, Indonesia

June 2017 – August 2017

IT Internship

- Team up and coordinated with the Android Developer Team
- Help to develop their new Android application especially on user interface and pulling data from their database
- Use SQLite to perform SQL queries on Android Studio

Projects

Movie Database Fall 2017

- Use Android Studio to create an application to show lists of new, popular and upcoming movies
- User will be able to login to write their review or read other user's review on a certain movie
- Use Firebase to store user's information and list of reviews on each movie

Who Will Carry?

Fall 2018

- Scraped the data frame from a website which contains performances of professional players in League of Legends from several season and region
- Clean the data from scraped tables to remove unreliable or missing values
- Create algorithms to calculate each player's value to team based on their position and performances
- Visualize the data in graphs and table in Shiny app

NCAA Fantasy Invest

- Worked with a team of four to create a web application for investing in NCAA Basketball players.
- Designed and developed frontend application using React and Material UI
- Designed backend API and database models using Python, Diango, Pandas and SOLite